Guide to the American Veterans Committee records, 1942-2002 MS2144
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Audio/visual, 1965-1993; MS2144 Series 15; 3.25 Linear feet
  - Saturday am #1 Human Resources [1/3], undated (Box 250, Folder 18)
    Transcribed and rewound 12/29/1966
  - Saturday am #2 Human Resources [2/3], undated (Box 250, Folder 19)
    Transcribed and rewound 12/28/1966
  - Saturday am #3 Panel V Human Resources [3/3], undated (Box 250, Folder 20)
  - Miss McGrath - Miss Liebler [1/2], undated (Box 250, Folder 21)
    Enclosed within an envelope dated 1966
  - Miss McGrath - Miss Liebler [2/2], undated (Box 250, Folder 22)
  - Human Rights of the Man in Uniform at GWU [1/3], 06/11/1968 (Box 250, Folder 23)
    06/11-12/1968 Opening Session GT Col Parker
  - Human Rights Seminar, Military Justice [2/3], 06/11/1968 (Box 250, Folder 24)
    Parker
  - Human Rights Seminar, Military Justice [3/3], 06/11/1968 (Box 250, Folder 25)
  - Human Rights Conference [1/8], 03/20/1970 (Box 250, Folder 26)
    Washington D.C., Hotel Sherman Park, Plenary Session 2:45 - 4 pm "Man in Uniform Vis a Vis Code of Conduct"
  - Dean Fairbanks Address, Luncheon Session [2/8], 03/20/1970 (Box 250, Folder 27)
  - Man in Uniform Vis a Vis POW Convention [3/8] Empty Reel [?], 03/21/1970 (Box 250, Folder 28)
  - Man in Uniform as Conscientious Objector [4/8], undated (Box 250, Folder 29)
    Rev Edward Swanson, Sat March 21 - 9-11AM
  - Man in Uniform as Conscientious Objector [5/8], 03/21/1970 (Box 250, Folder 30)
    Cont'd 9-11 AM Plenary Session Tape 2, Col Tyson, Mike Wittell, Jack Pemberton
  - Man in Uniform as Conscientious Objector [6/8], 03/21/1970 (Box 250, Folder 31)
    Sat March 21, 9-11, 1970
  - Congressman Biaggi Dinner Speech [7/8], 03/21/1970 (Box 250, Folder 32)
  - Man in Uniform Vis a Vis International Community [8/8], 03/22/1970 (Box 250, Folder 33)
    Sun Mar 22, 1970 Plenary Session
  - Dr. F. Masi Box 46, APO 09405 NY NY, 04/24/1970 (Box 250, Folder 34)
  - 1970 Convention Banquet (Box 250, Folder 35)
  - Newsroom Dub, Tom Corpora on Discharges, 09/23/1971 (Box 250, Folder 36)
  - All Things Considered Tape of Radio Interview for Becky White, 05/29/1972 (Box 250, Folder 37)
    John Valentine, Skip Roberts, Ernie Meyer
  - Gartenhaus Interview, Mrs. June Willenz Ex. Director of Veteran Committee, 04/22/1973 (Box 250, Folder 38)
    Air: April 22, 1973 Time: 6:38
  - NEC Meeting New York, 05/23/1974 (Box 250, Folder 39)
  - AVC Convention 1983 [1/2], 06/24/1983 -- -- --06/26/1983 (Box 250, Folder 40)
    Includes: 1. Women Vets Panel 2. Health Care, Hutton, Kilborne
  - AVC Convention 1983 [2/2], undated (Box 250, Folder 41)
    Includes: 1. Health Care Panel - cont'd, Dr. Hutchins, Dr. Wilder 2. Dr. Bloom, Lois Hull, HV Will
  - AVC Files for '92 Board Mtg, 1992 (Box 250, Folder 42)
    Content unknown
  - Tapes - Nann Hearings, Gays in Military, 03/31/1993 (Box 250, Folder 43)
    3 microcassettes are included.
  - Alternatives to S-S- and [meci] educational Ramification, undated (Box 251, Folder 1)
    Sat Workshop Education
  - AVC Morning Sessions, Education and Returning Veterans [1/2], undated (Box 251, Folder 2)
    Wed 5/23, First part of afternoon Wed
  - AVC 2nd part of Conference, Education and Returning Veterans [2/2], undated (Box 251, Folder 3)
  - 7 - Civil Rights, undated (Box 251, Folder 4)
  - Cleo New Tape [1/2], undated (Box 251, Folder 5)
  - Cleo New Tape [2/2], undated (Box 251, Folder 6)
  - CO Session June + [kardultrin] Tape 4, undated (Box 251, Folder 7)
  - Debate the Draft, WETA AM, Veterans Committee, undated (Box 251, Folder 8)
    Attn, Mrs. Willenz
  - #4 Hamilton Rm Education, undated (Box 251, Folder 9)
    Content Unknown
  - 5 Illegal Orders - Conv Comm, Andy Rice, Chman - etc, undated (Box 251, Folder 10)
  - James Empty Reel, undated (Box 251, Folder 11)
  - #5 Partisan Politics and Corruption in Government, undated (Box 251, Folder 12)
  - 3. Political Rights, undated (Box 251, Folder 13)
    Webster for Ridordan; Rowland Watts; Col. Hays; Mr. Stapp
  - 4 Social and Economic Speeches and most of discussion, undated (Box 251, Folder 14)
  - 2 West - Col Kent - Prof Sherman, undated (Box 251, Folder 15)
  - 1 2 3 4 5 6 7, undated (Box 251, Folder 16)
  - [No Title], undated (Box 251, Folder 17)
  - AVC Files for '92 Board Meeting, 1992 (Box 252, Folder 1)
    Addressed and dated envelope which held floppy disk. Floppy disk stored in box 250 folder 42
  - Citizens First - Radio Program Instructions, 08/13/1966 (Box 252, Folder 2)
    Instruction for radio program. Magnetic tape stored in box 250 folder 4
  - Class Two Deferments, Draft and Human Resources, Complete Statement of Betty M. Vetter, 08/13/1966 (Box 252, Folder 3)
    Transcribed complete statement of Betty M. Vetter. Magnetic tape stored in box 250 folder 15
  - Cleo New Tape - Note of schedule to Chairman of Workshop, undated (Box 252, Folder 4)
    Note to Chairman of Workshop. Magnetic tapes stored in box 0251 folders 5 and 6
  - Contract w/ Dept of Labor for Women Veterans in workplace, 09/22/1983 (Box 252, Folder 5)
    Contract to develop a concept paper for assessing military to civilian skill of women veterans. Audiocassettes stored in box 250 folders 40 and 41
  - Miss McGrath - Miss Liebler, envelope, undated (Box 252, Folder 6)
    Envelope sent to June Willenz Nov 1966. Magnetic tapes stored in box 250 folders 21 and 22
- Artifacts, 1945-1985; MS2144 Series 16; 2.25 Linear feet
  The materials of this series include banners, hats, armbands, flags, pins, posters, and bumper stickers, as well as award certificates and medals given and received by the American Veterans Committee. Also included are unique items such as doodles, drawings created by AVC members during meetings. The materials range in date from 1945 to 1985 and provide physical evidence of most of the activities conducted by the Committee.
  Many of the items were originally used at AVC national conventions and ceremonies. This is especially true of the certificates and awards. In this category, the Hubert Will Award given to Congressman Thomas Downey, Phineas Indritz, and Hubert Will are prominent. There is also the George Norris Civil Rights Award to Monsignor Geno Boroni. Additional items of note include the "credo of a public servant" and a signed Human Goals Pledge with signatures from the leaders of the Veterans Administration.
  Parade materials are also prominent. The banners and flags of the AVC, along with marching paraphenalia are held within this series.
  - "Doodles" By Mike Straight, 1950 (Box 255, Folder 1)
    Drawings of people and things created by Mike Straight.
  - "Doodles" (By AVCers), undated (Box 255, Folder 2)
    Drawings of people and other objects.
  - AVC Citizens First Awards, 05/08/1985 (Box 255, Folder 4)
    Presented to Hon. Max Kampelman, Dr. Arthur Flemming, Esther Peterson, Harold Russell
  - AVC Certificate of Membership of President's Committee on Employment of Handicapped, 1966-1977 (Box 255, Folder 5)
    Certificate states that AVC is a member of President's Committee on Employment of Handicapped
  - AVC Awards for Hubert Will, 11/11/1958-05/17/1976 (Box 255, Folder 6)
    Award Certificates and two letters for the Honorable Howard Will
  - Credo of a Public Servant, undated (Box 255, Folder 7)
    Printed like a certificate, this is a credo for people holding a government post
  - Service Award Certificates, undated (Box 255, Folder 8)
    AVC Award Certificates with no recipient named
  - Join AVC Bumper Stickers, undated (Box 255, Folder 9)
    Two bumper stickers
  - Citizens First Awards and Eleanor Roosevelt Citizenship Awards, 06/25/1983 (Box 255, Folder 10)
    Citizens First Awards presented to Congressman Thomas Downey, Roosevelt Awards presented to Phineas Indritz
  - Veterans Administration Volunteer Service Award to AVC, 10/26/1981 (Box 255, Folder 11)
    Volunteer Service Award presented to American Veterans Committee
  - Veterans Administration Human Goals w/ Signatures, undated (Box 255, Folder 12)
    Human Goals Pledge with signatures of the leaders of the Veterans Administration
  - George W. Norris Civil Rights Award, 06/26/1976 (Box 255, Folder 13)
    To Monsignor Geno Baroni
  - State of New York Certificate of Incorporation of AVC, Inc., 05/24/1945 (Box 255, Folder 14)
  - AVC Three Founders Award for Hubert Will, 04/10/1976 (Box 255, Folder 15)
  - Veterans Administration Voluntary Service Certificate to American Veterans Committee, 04/18/1966 (Box 255, Folder 16)
  - Veterans Administration Voluntary Service Award to AVC "30 Years of Democracy in Action", 10/1976 (Box 255, Folder 17)
  - Join AVC Posters, undated (Box 256, Folder 1)
    Three rolled posters are included
  - AVC Pins, Veterans' Poppy Day Association of Chicago pin, a medal, stamps, emblem, and key, undated (Box 257, Folder 1)
  - AVC Pennant Twelfth National Convention, undated (Box 257, Folder 2)
  - AVC Bessie Levine Memorial Award [Plaque with no inscription], undated (Box 257, Folder 3)
  - AVC Arm Bands, Yellow and Blue, undated (Box 257, Folder 4)
    Four AVC Arms Bands
  - Gold Cord, as part of parade ensemble, undated (Box 257, Folder 5)
  - Ribbons, AVC 40th Anniversary National Convention, 06/29/1984-07/1/1984 (Box 257, Folder 6)
    Two ribbons enclosed
  - Belt with flag holster, undated (Box 257, Folder 7)
    For carrying and supporting flag during a parade
  - Lane Bryant Annual Award for 1949 Presented to Greater Washington AVC Clubhouse [plaque], 11/21/1950 (Box 257, Folder 8)
  - Frank E. G. Weil Desk Name Plate, undated (Box 257, Folder 9)
  - AVC Hats, undated (Box 257, Folder 10)
    Five hats included
  - United States Flag, undated (Box 257, Folder 11)
  - United States Flag, undated (Box 257, Folder 12)
  - World Veterans Federation Banner, undated (Box 257, Folder 13)
  - AVC Banner, Franklin D. Roosevelt Chapter, Bronx, New York, undated (Box 258, Folder 1)
  - AVC Banner, with Citizens First in the 80s ribbon, undated (Box 258, Folder 2)